<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;श्री-वैष्णव on भाषान्तरेषु विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/gadyam/shrI-vaiShNava/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;श्री-वैष्णव on भाषान्तरेषु विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/gadyam/shrI-vaiShNava/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>shrI-vaiShNava-paribhAShA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/gadyam/shrI-vaiShNava/shrI-vaiShNava-paribhAShA/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/gadyam/shrI-vaiShNava/shrI-vaiShNava-paribhAShA/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://archive.org/details/in.ernet.dli.2015.384510/mode/2up&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;TODO: Proofread&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;श्रीवैष्णव परिभाषैयुम्&#xA;सिल सत्विषय्ङ्गळुम्&#xA;ISSUED FREE WITH&#xA;NITYAANUSANDHAANAM &amp;amp; NITYAANUSHTAANAKRAMAM&#xA;तॊगुप्पु:&#xA;स्वधर्मनिरद, शिष्टप्रेष्ट, सकलगलागुसल्,&#xA;सॆन्नॆऱिच् चॆम्मल्, श्री हयक्रीवदास वे. वेङ्गडेसन्&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1977&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;०&#34;&gt;०&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;वणपपणम&#34;&gt;वणिप्पणम्&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;अन्बुम् अरुळुम् अरुङ्गुणमुम् निऱैन्दवरुम्, तिरु मालिन् तिरुवडियैच् चिन्दैयिलुम्, सिरत्तिलुम् तिनमुम् सूडिप् पोट्रुबवरुम्, उबयगलैयैच् चेर्न्द तिरुमाल् अन्बर् कळिडमुम्, सिवनेयर्गळिडमुम् अन्बु सॆलुत्तुबवरुम्, लिप्को निऱुवनत्तिन् स्ताबगरुमान श्री सडारि सेवग पक्तिप्रस रणप्रवीण, श्री हयक्रीवसेवारत्नम् श्री उ.वे. तिरुमलै तल्लान् सक्रवर्त्ति व.किरुष्णस्वामि सर्मा स्वामि आस्तिग उलगिऱ्‌काग माबॆरुम् तॊण्डु सॆय्दुवरुवदु यावरुम् अऱिन् ददे.उबयगलैयैच् चेर्न्द श्री वैष्णवर्गळ् ऒट्रुमैयुडन् वाऴ्न्दु वरुवदन्मूलम्, पडिप्पडियाग उलग सगोदरत्वम् एऱ्‌पड वेण्डुम् ऎन्बदु इप्पॆरियवरिन् ऒरे अबिलाषै. इवरुडैय इन्द मनोरदम् निऱैवेऱ वेण्डुमॆण्ड्रु श्रीबॆरुम्बुदूर् वन्द वळ्ळल् (तिरुमलै, तिरुनारायणबुरम्, मदुरान्दगम्, तिरुवहीन्दिरबुरम् मुदलिय पल तिव्यदेशङ्गळिल् सेवै तरुम्) श्री भगवत् रामानुजर् तिरुवडिगळिल् इच्चिऱु नूलै वॆगु उरुक्कत्तुडनुम्, महा विसुवासत्तुडनुम् समर्प् पिक्किऱेन्.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>नित्यानुसन्धानम्</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/gadyam/shrI-vaiShNava/nityAnusandhAnam/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/tamiL/gadyam/shrI-vaiShNava/nityAnusandhAnam/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://archive.org/details/in.ernet.dli.2015.384510/page/n57/mode/1up&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;TODO: Proofread&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;००&#34;&gt;००&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;en&#34;&gt;En&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;PREPARATION OF A SMALL BOOK FOR THE PURPOSE OF DAILY PRAYERS BY EACH SISHYA IN PRAISE OF HIS&#xA;AACHARYA&#xA;It is no exageration to say that the Gnanam,Vairaagyam and Anush- taanam of Sri Ubhaya Ve. Vidwan, Siromani, Vidya Visaarada, Nyaya Vedanta Praveena, Sri Desika Dar- sana Dhurandara Vangeepuram Nava- neetham Opiliyappankoil Srirama- desikacharya Swami is beyond des- cription.&#xA;He is said to have thousands of Sishyas and so the Sishyas thought it fit to print a small book in regard to their own daily Anushtaanam,&#xA;This book is reproduced in full below so that the Sishyas belonging to other Aachaaryas can emulate this example. They are advised to buy a Students&amp;rsquo; Bound Note Book and copy out similar prayers and directions with the help of any great scholar or Aacharya.&#xA;Such a book should be preserved with extreme care and with Maha Visvaasam.&#xA;Then all shall be well with the Srivaishnavite World as a whole.&#xA;SARVE JANAAS SUKHINO BHAVANTHUI LOKAASS SAMASTHAAS SUKIHINO BHAVANTHU I SARVE BHADRAANI PASYANTHUI&#xA;SAMASTHA SANMANGALAANI SANTHU 1&#xA;OM SAANTHIS SAANTHIS SANTHIHI I&#xA;With prayerful greetings from: THE LIFCO PUBLISHERS, MADRAS- 600017.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
