<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;मानसतरङ्गिणीकृल्-लेखाः on भाषान्तरेषु विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/prakIrNAryabhAShAH/meta/MT_lekhAH/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;मानसतरङ्गिणीकृल्-लेखाः on भाषान्तरेषु विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2006 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/prakIrNAryabhAShAH/meta/MT_lekhAH/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Maharatti and Kannada and more musing on Indo-Aryan</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/prakIrNAryabhAShAH/meta/MT_lekhAH/2006-07-16_maharatti-and-kannada-and-more-musing-on-indo-aryan/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/prakIrNAryabhAShAH/meta/MT_lekhAH/2006-07-16_maharatti-and-kannada-and-more-musing-on-indo-aryan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2006/07/16/maharatti-and-kannada-and-more-musing-on-indo-aryan/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Obivously, Indo-Aryan and Dravidian have been at the center of my&#xA;linguistic interests because they are the very basis of my cultural and&#xA;genetic heritage. During my peregrinations in the peninsula I made some&#xA;observations, and read a work of KM Munshi that the muni brought to my&#xA;attention, which resulted in a flash. This concerns the relationship&#xA;between Maharatti the Indo-Aryan language of the northern peninsula and&#xA;the Aryanized Dravidian language Kannada that is a bit further south.&#xA;The first great empire of this region was the Andhra empire of the&#xA;shatavAhana that held sway within the interval 2ooBCE-200 CE. The&#xA;principal language of this empire was a middle Indo-Aryan dialect, a&#xA;prakR^it, mahArAShTri prakR^it that was used fairly extensively as a&#xA;commercial, official and literary language. This contention is most&#xA;effectively confirmed by the literary work in this language, sattasai of&#xA;the andhra king hAla. We see its extensive effects in the Aryanization&#xA;of the peninsula, including the older IA superstrate on Tamil, Kannada&#xA;and Telugu. Its use an official language probably contributed to its use&#xA;in classical Sanskrit dramatics as the epitome of a barbarous prakR^it&#xA;spoken by the lower sections of society. For example, note its use as&#xA;the language of the crude characters in the play AgamaDambara, much&#xA;later in time, by the Kashimirian brAhmin jayanta bhaTTa. This prakR^it&#xA;clear shares some synapomorphies with modern Maharatti, suggesting that&#xA;it indeed directly contributed as an ancestor of the local IA language&#xA;of modern times.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The substrate in Old Indo-Aryan</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/prakIrNAryabhAShAH/meta/MT_lekhAH/2006-07-16_the-substrate-in-old-indo-aryan/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/prakIrNAryabhAShAH/meta/MT_lekhAH/2006-07-16_the-substrate-in-old-indo-aryan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2006/07/16/the-substrate-in-old-indo-aryan/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Over the past century Western as well as Hindu investigators have noted&#xA;the substrate in Indo-Aryan. However, identifying its origin has been&#xA;largely left to the speculative whims of the worker. Dravidian and&#xA;Austro-Asiatic have been the pet choices, but there are serious problems&#xA;with each of these. A proper objective reconstruction of native&#xA;proto-Dravidian has not been carried out to discern true transfers from&#xA;Dravidian to IA. There is a heavy weighting favor of Tamil- but then&#xA;Tamil is not proto-Dravidian and Tamil was influenced prior to its&#xA;earliest attestation by IA. In contrast, the oldest IA shows now signs&#xA;of Dravidian. So the directionality, except for the obvious cases is&#xA;hardly clear. Of the two Austro-Asiatic branches, Munda (the Munda&#xA;branch) is distributed more widely within the modern IA spread (though&#xA;with an Eastern epicenter), and Khasi belonging to the other subfamily&#xA;(Mon-Khmer) is in the far east of India at the border of the current IA&#xA;dominant zone. Both genetics (the O3e Y-chromosomal marker) and skeletal&#xA;anatomy suggest that the Austro-Asiatic spread was limited to an Eastern&#xA;population, though historical it may have stretched as far as the&#xA;Narmada valley north of Maharashtra. Secondly, it is found mainly in&#xA;tribal populations that are relatively disjoint from each other. In&#xA;light of this claims for Austro-Asiatic in Vedic and Sanskrit should be&#xA;considered more carefully. One well known class of words that has caught&#xA;everyone’s attention as a major substrate in Sanskrit (OIA) are the&#xA;words with the prefix ka-, ki-, kI-, ku-, ke-, followed usually by an&#xA;element that does not have an obvious IA (IE) etymology. These words&#xA;have been considered definitive cases of Austro-Asiatic lateral&#xA;transfers, especially by pointing to the presence of articles in Khasi&#xA;like feminine ka- and plural ki. While in principle this theory is&#xA;plausible it has problems: Proper, objective Austro-Asiatic etymologies&#xA;have not yet been furnished for the majority of such words in IA.&#xA;Secondly, Khasi is a very Eastern branch of AA and these words are seen&#xA;from the early layers of IA. This is not consistent with the genetics of&#xA;Austro-Asiatic populations or their distribution. Again even learned&#xA;scholars like Masica have differently etymologized words of this&#xA;striking structure, sometimes calling them AA and other times Dr. Thus,&#xA;there appears to be lack of clarity regarding their origin. Whatever the&#xA;case we believe that the case for them being AA is far from certain, but&#xA;they were definitely derived from the major language spoken in India&#xA;before the advent of IA. The famous word karpAsa in Sanskrit is believed&#xA;to be derived from this substrate and follows the very typical structure&#xA;of such words. Given that it was attested in Mesopotamia as an Indic&#xA;word, the general consensus is that words with the ka-,ki-,kI-, ku-&#xA;structure were present in the Indus language, irrespective of whether it&#xA;was Austro-Asiatic or an unknown family. Let examine some of these words&#xA;that are particularly over-represented in names of plants usually&#xA;peculiar to India:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
