<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Articles on भाषान्तरेषु विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/latina/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Articles on भाषान्तरेषु विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/latina/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Classicists and sight-reading Latin</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/latina/articles/classicists_and_sight-reading_latin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/latina/articles/classicists_and_sight-reading_latin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Latin as She is Spoke: How Classicists Tricked Themselves, and the Real Issue with Mary Beard&amp;rsquo;s Latin&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blogicarian.blogspot.com/2019/03/argumentum-ad-ignorantiam.html?m=0&#34;&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A.Z. Foreman is a translator and poet who has been obsessed with languages and literature since childhood&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Not long ago, Mary Beard graced us with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.the-tls.co.uk/what-does-the-latin-actually-say/&#34;&gt;a bit of honorable honesty&lt;/a&gt; in the Times Literary Supplement, in which she confessed to what is a bit of an open secret among most classicists. She can&amp;rsquo;t sight-read a complex Latin text all that well. Most classicists can&amp;rsquo;t. This admission — from someone like Beard — is good to have out there.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Orthography</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/latina/articles/orthography_reference/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/bhAShAntaram/latina/articles/orthography_reference/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: AryAMsha&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;length&#34;&gt;Length&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;ă - it’s called a breve, it marks a short a&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;ā - a macron marks a long a, two matras long&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The dictionary (LSJ) in particular doesnt mark final and initial shorts -&#xA;angărĭa is actually ăngărĭă. They assume you know that final /a/ is always short unless specified.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Post medieval latin doesnt mark macrons. However, all modern textbooks that teach latin mark macrons.&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Greek orthography is much more conservative here, they always mark pitch accent (udatta, anudatta etc). You have to learn how to mark the accent in all nouns and verbs when writing greek and even in medieval times they used to write the accent&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;most people don’t write ă because its more work, so they just leave it as “a”&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;looking-up-words&#34;&gt;Looking up words&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;noun stem in latin is identical to nominative singular, which you will try to guess from the form.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;we cannot form our own nouns, own adjectives just from dhAtus using krit or taddhita pratyayas. this exists in greek, but also to a reduced extent. skt is much more flexible here.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;learning&#34;&gt;Learning&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;I also recommend Lingua latina per se illustrata (Pars 1 Familia Romana) book series for learning latin. Its the only thing anyone needs, nothing else needed. it teaches latin in latin, not a word of english used.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
